Guide to the John R. Mott Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Notes and Notebooks, 1907-1937, nd.; Series IV
  - Travel notes, itineraries, 1901-1907 (Box 130, Folder 2111)
  - Travel notes, itineraries, 1909 (Box 130, Folder 2112)
  - Travel notes, itineraries, 1912-1919 (Box 130, Folder 2113)
  - Travel notes, itineraries, 1920-1924 (Box 130, Folder 2114)
  - Travel notes, itineraries, 1925-1927 (Box 130, Folder 2115)
  - Travel notes, itineraries, 1929-1933 (Box 130, Folder 2116)
  - Travel notes, itineraries, 1934-1938 (Box 130, Folder 2117)
  - Travel notes, itineraries, 1940-1945 (Box 130, Folder 2118)
  - Travel notes, itineraries, 1946-1948 (Box 131, Folder 2119)
  - Travel notes, itineraries, 1949-1951 (Box 131, Folder 2120)
  - Travel notes, itineraries 2121A United War Work Campaign n.d. (Box 131, Folder 2121)
  - Upper Iowa University - address, 1943 (Box 131, Folder 2122)
  - War relief, 1937-1940, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 2123)
  - Washington Cathedral, 1925-1941 (Box 131, Folder 2124)
  - World Council of Churches, 1938-1951, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 2125)
  - World Council of Churches - Interna- national Missionary Council - Joint Committee, 1939-1947, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 2126)
  - World War I, 1915-1918 (Box 131, Folder 2127)
  - World War I, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 2128)
  - World War I, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 2129)
  - World War II, 1939-1945 (Box 131, Folder 2130)
  - World War II, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 2131)
  - World's Student Christian Federation, 1895-1909 (Box 131, Folder 2132)
  - World's Student Christian Federation, 1911-1919 (Box 131, Folder 2133)
  - World's Student Christian Federation, 1921-1946 (Box 131, Folder 2134)
  - World's Student Christian Federation, n.d. (Box 132, Folder 2135)
  - YMCA - Boy's Work, 1899-1939 (Box 132, Folder 2136)
  - YMCA - General, 1893-1904 (Box 132, Folder 2137)
  - YMCA - General, 1905-1908 (Box 132, Folder 2138)
  - YMCA - General, 1909-1910 (Box 132, Folder 2139)
  - YMCA - General, 1911-1920 (Box 132, Folder 2140)
  - YMCA - General, 1921-1922 (Box 132, Folder 2141)
  - YMCA - General, 1923-1924 (Box 132, Folder 2142)
  - YMCA - General, 1925-1926 (Box 132, Folder 2143)
  - YMCA - General, 1927-1928 (Box 132, Folder 2144)
  - YMCA - General, 1929-1930 (Box 132, Folder 2145)
  - YMCA - General, 1931-1939 (Box 132, Folder 2146)
  - YMCA - General, 1941-1947 (Box 132, Folder 2147)
  - YMCA - General, n.d. (Box 132, Folder 2148)
  - YMCA - General, n.d. (Box 132, Folder 2149)
  - YMCA - Relationship to the churches, 1909-1921, n.d. (Box 133, Folder 2150)
  - YMCA - Retirement Fund, 1921, n.d. (Box 133, Folder 2151)
  - YMCA - Secretaryship, 1902-1941, n.d. (Box 133, Folder 2152)
  - YMCA - Student Division (See also: Student Christian Work), 1888-1941 (Box 133, Folder 2153)
  - YMCA - Student Division, n.d. (Box 133, Folder 2154)
  - YMCA - Student Division (notebook), 1890 (Box 133, Folder 2155)
  - YMCA - Student Division (notebook), 1892 (Box 133, Folder 2156)
  - YMCA - Student Division (notebook), 1894-1899 (Box 133, Folder 2157)
  - YMCA - Student Division (notebook), 1899 (Box 133, Folder 2158)
  - YMCA - Student Division (notebook) n,d. (Box 133, Folder 2159)
  - YMCA - War Work, 1942-1945 (Box 133, Folder 2160)
  - YMCA - War Work, 1915-1922 (Box 133, Folder 2161)
  - YMCA - War Work, n.d. (Box 133, Folder 2162)
  - YMCA, n.d. (Box 134, Folder 2163)
  - Youth, 1930-1942, n.d. (Box 134, Folder 2164)
  - Leila White Mott Notebooks, 1886-1887 (Box 134, Folder 2165)
  - Leila White Mott Notebooks, 1895, 1912 (Box 134, Folder 2166)
  - Leila White Mott Notebooks, 1927, 1936 (Box 134, Folder 2167)
  - Leila White Mott Notebooks, 1940-1941 (Box 134, Folder 2168)
  - Leila White Mott Notebooks, n.d. (Box 134, Folder 2169)
  - Leila White Mott Miscellaneous holograph notes (Box 134, Folder 2170)
  - Leila White Mott Miscellaneous holograph notes (Box 134, Folder 2171)
  - Leila White Mott Miscellaneous holograph notes (Box 135, Folder 2172)
  - Leila White Mott Miscellaneous holograph notes (Box 135, Folder 2173)
  - Leila White Mott Notes re: Bible Study (Box 135, Folder 2174)
  - Leila White Mott Notes re: Bible Study (Box 135, Folder 2175)
  - Leila White Mott Printed and Typescript material (Box 135, Folder 2176)
- Addresses and Articles, Series V
  A. Leadership
  1. Biographies of individuals
  2. General: including re.the enlistment and qualities of leaders
  B. Church, Church union
  C. Devotional, evangelistic: including re: Christian character and JRM's personal religious experience.
  D. International situation
  1. General
  2. Africa
  3. Asia (including Australia)
  4. Europe
  5. Latin America
  6. Near East
  7. Russia
  E. Missions: including domestic missions and the general theory of foreign missions. Addresses and articles related to missions in Specific foreign countries are located in Section D.
  F. Money
  G. Prohibition
  H. Specific organizations: relating to the history and purpose of the organization or known to have been specifically addressed to the organization
  1. British and Foreign Bible Society
  2. International Missionary Council
  3. Methodist Church (in U.S. and Britain)
  4. Student Volunteer Movement
  5. WSCF
  6. YMCA
  - Leadership
    - Biography
      - Barbour, C.R., 1937 (Box 136, Folder 2177)
      - Brainerd, Cephas, 1945 (Box 136, Folder 2177)
      - Brenner, Dr., 1944 (Box 136, Folder 2177)
      - Brockman, Fletcher, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 2178)
      - Dodge, Grace, 1915 (Box 136, Folder 2178)
      - Eddy, Sherwood, 1931 (Box 136, Folder 2179)
      - Fry, Wilfred, 1932 (Box 136, Folder 2179)
      - Harmon, Francis, 1932 (Box 136, Folder 2180)
      - Hoover, Herbert, 1928, 1932 (Box 136, Folder 2180)
      - Hyde, A.A., 1925 (Box 136, Folder 2180)
      - Irving, George, 1937 (Box 136, Folder 2181)
      - McBee, Silas, 1924 (Box 136, Folder 2181)
      - McBurney, Robert, 1899 (Box 136, Folder 2181)
      - Moody, Dwight., 1915, 1937 (Box 136, Folder 2182)
      - Morse, Richard, 1926, 1927 (Box 136, Folder 2182)
      - Murray, William D, c. 1939 (Box 136, Folder 2182)
      - Paton, William, 1944 (Box 136, Folder 2182)
      - Ross, Emory, 1940 (Box 136, Folder 2183)
      - Soderblom, Nathan, 1933 (Box 136, Folder 2183)
      - Speer, Robert E., 1948 (Box 136, Folder 2183)
      - Rose, Horace William, 1904 (Box 136, Folder 2184)
      - Temple, William, 1945 (Box 136, Folder 2185)
      - Weidensall, Robert, 1918 (Box 136, Folder 2185)
      - Wilson, C.E., n.d. (Box 136, Folder 2185)
    - General
      - Morality in American Politics, 1884 (Box 136, Folder 2186)
      - Points of Weakness in a College A Association President, 1891 (Box 136, Folder 2186)
      - Physical, Intellectual and Spiritual Life of the Secretary, 1898 (Box 136, Folder 2187)
      - An Appeal for Christian Workers, 1902 (Box 136, Folder 2187)
      - Claims and Opportunities of the Christian Ministry (pamphlet series edited by JRM), 1909 (Box 136, Folder 2188)
      - How to Secure Spontaneous and Enduring Activity on the Part of Voluntary Workers, 1912 (Box 136, Folder 2189)
      - Voluntary Workers Worth While, 1912 (Box 136, Folder 2189)
      - The World's Need of Workers, 1919 (Box 136, Folder 2190)
      - The Opportunity of the Professor for Christian Work among Students (Box 136, Folder 2190)
      - Maintaining and Enlarging Leadership, 1920 (Box 136, Folder 2191)
      - Factors Underlying the Leadership of the Railways of America, 1922 (Box 136, Folder 2191)
      - Legislative and Executive Functions, 1922 (Box 136, Folder 2192)
      - How to Augment the Leadership of the Missionary Forces at the Home Base, 1923 (Box 136, Folder 2192)
      - Leadership of the Constructive Forces of the World, 1931 (Box 136, Folder 2193)
      - Leadership Demanded for This Momentous Time, 1945-1947 (Box 136, Folder 2193)
      - Leadership Demanded in This Momentous Time (Nobel Prize Address), 1946 (Box 136, Folder 2194)
      - The Intellectual Life of the Secretary, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 2195)
      - Need of Men of Power, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 2195)
      - The Price of Leadership, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 2195)
  - Church, Church Union
    - The Causes of the Reformation, 1884 (Box 137, Folder 2196)
    - A Great Lay Brotherhood - Lessons in True Fraternity, 1894 (Box 137, Folder 2196)
    - Our Oneness in Jesus Christ, 1902 (Box 137, Folder 2197)
    - Man's Need of the Church, 1913, 1914 (Box 137, Folder 2197)
    - Principles to Guide in Co-operative Relations of Christian Organizations, 1916 (Box 137, Folder 2198)
    - The Prices to Be Paid to Ensure The Most Effective and Fruitful Cooperation, 1922 (Box 137, Folder 2198)
    - The Price to Be Paid to Ensure Christian Unity, 1932 (Box 137, Folder 2199)
    - Expectations Concerning the Approaching Ecumenical Conference at Oxford, 1937 (Box 137, Folder 2200)
    - The Significance of the Oxford and Edinburgh Ecumenical Conferences, 1937 (Box 137, Folder 2200)
    - The Unifying Influence of the Washington Cathedral, 1937 (Box 137, Folder 2201)
    - Letter to Christendom, 1938 (Box 137, Folder 2201)
    - The Cost of Ecumenical Unity, 1941 (Box 137, Folder 2202)
    - Counting the Cost of Ecumenicity, 1941 (Box 137, Folder 2202)
    - The Price We Must Pay for The Realization of the Ecumenical Ideal, 1941 (Box 137, Folder 2202)
    - What Price Our Ecumenical Ideal?, 1941 (Box 137, Folder 2202)
    - Unite to Co-operate, 1942 (Box 137, Folder 2203)
    - The Ecumenical Advance of the Decade, c. 1947 (Box 137, Folder 2204)
    - Amsterdam: An Ecumenical Milestone, 1948 (Box 137, Folder 2204)
    - From Edinburgh 1910 to Amsterdam 1948 (Box 137, Folder 2205)
    - From Edinburgh to Amsterdam 1948 (Box 137, Folder 2205)
  - Devotional, Evangelistic
    - An Anchored Life, 1885 (Box 137, Folder 2206)
    - What We Owe the Twentieth Century, 1885 (Box 137, Folder 2206)
    - Bible Study Topical Studies and Plans of Work 1889 for Bible Training Classes (with C.K. Ober), 1888 (Box 137, Folder 2207)
    - The Morning Watch, 1893-1925 (Box 137, Folder 2208)
    - Bible Study for Personal Spiritual, 1895-1925 (Box 137, Folder 2209)
    - Secret Prayer The Secret Prayer Life 1896-1932 (Box 137, Folder 2210)
    - Address on Receipt of Honorary M.A. from Yale, 1899 (Box 137, Folder 2211)
    - Be Sure Your Sins Will Find You Out, 1900
    - The Enrichment of Personal Life, c. 1900
    - Bible Study, 1900 (Box 137, Folder 2212)
    - The Need of More Evangelistic Spirit in Our Colleges, 1900
    - The College Man's Religion at the Beginning of the Twentieth Century, 1901 (Box 137, Folder 2213)
    - Incentives to Prayer for A Spiritual Awakening in Colleges, 1901
    - Be Filled with The Spirit, 1902 (Box 137, Folder 2214)
    - The Holy Spirit The Source of Power, 1902
    - Temptations of Students (with Japanese translation), 1902 (Box 137, Folder 2215)
    - The Use of the Tongue, 1902
    - Religious Meditation, 1902-1904 (Box 137, Folder 2216)
    - The Power Essential for the Making Of a Christian Man, 1902 (Box 137, Folder 2217)
    - The Deity of Jesus Christ, 1903
    - Individual Work for Individuals, 1903-1944 (Box 137, Folder 2218)
    - The Perils of a Religious Conference, 1903 (Box 137, Folder 2219)
    - The Power of Jesus Christ in Life of Student, 1903, 1904
    - The Power of Sin, 1903 (Box 138, Folder 2220)
    - Principles and Helps in Determining a Life-Work, 1903
    - Why an Increasing Number of Young Men throughout the World Believe in Jesus Christ as Lord, 1903-1908 (Box 138, Folder 2221)
    - Spiritual Atrophy, 1904 (Box 138, Folder 2222)
    - Christ, a Reality (Jeesus Kristus todellismus), 1905, 1909
    - How May Jesus Christ Become a Reality to Me?, 1905-1914 (Box 138, Folder 2223)
    - The Power of Jesus Christ in the Life of the Student, 1905 (Box 138, Folder 2224)
    - The Spread of Christ's Kingdom among Men, 1905
    - Consecration, 1908 (Box 138, Folder 2225)
    - Our Religion Primarily a Matter of the Will, 1908
    - The Attractiveness of Hardship in the Ministry, 1908
    - The Fires of Evangelism, 1909 (Box 138, Folder 2226)
    - A Book of Power, 1910
    - Intercessors the Primary Need (with Korean and Portuguese translations), 1910-1914 (Box 138, Folder 2227)
    - The Battle with Impurity, 1911 (Box 138, Folder 2228)
    - What is the Secret of a Winning Life?, 1911
    - How Other Students Won the Victory over Temptation and Sin, 1911 (Box 138, Folder 2229)
    - The Realization of Christ, 1911
    - Seams of Weakness, 1911 (Box 138, Folder 2230)
    - Will-power and Religion, 1911
    - Constructive Suggestions for Character Building (with G.S. Eddy), 1912-1914 (Box 138, Folder 2231)
    - Intercessory Prayer, 1914
    - Moral and Spiritual Atrophy, 1914 (Box 138, Folder 2232)
    - Why a Young Man Needs Religion, 1916
    - The World's Need of Workers, 1919
    - Battleground of Students in All Lands, 1920 (Box 138, Folder 2233)
    - Men of Power, 1920
    - Seeking His Face, 1920 (Box 138, Folder 2234)
    - The Spirit of Sacrifice, 1920
    - Hindrances to the Spiritual Life, 1922 (Box 138, Folder 2235)
    - Meditation, 1922
    - Spiritual Realization and Spiritual Renewal, 1922, 1926 (Box 138, Folder 2236)
    - Our Greatest Need - A Fresh Accession of Vital Energy, 1923 (Box 138, Folder 2237)
    - Boyhood - The Greatest Asset of Any Nation, 1924
    - The Commitment of Life, 1924 (Box 138, Folder 2238)
    - re: Early Christian Experiences of JRM, 1924
    - Spiritual Atrophy (with Spanish translation), 1924, 1941 (Box 138, Folder 2239)
    - Spiritual Realization and Spiritual Renewal (alternate text), 1924
    - Fight for Character, 1925 (Box 139, Folder 2240)
    - Some Principles to Guide Us in the Use of Our Lives, 1925
    - Co-operation in Work for School Boys, 1926
    - Have I Not Seen Jesus Our Lord?, 1926 (Box 139, Folder 2241)
    - The Place Wherein Thou Standest is Holy Ground, 1926
    - World Trends and the Dedication of the Student Is Life, 1926 (Box 139, Folder 2242)
    - Securing Leaders, 1926
    - A Call to the Week of Prayer and to the World Study of Jesus, 1927 (Box 139, Folder 2243)
    - The Seeret of Victory Over Temptation, 1927
    - The Summons to a Larger Evangelism, 1929, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 2244)
    - My 40 years Have Taught Me to Trust Youth, 1930 (Box 139, Folder 2245)
    - Re: Early Christian Experiences of JRM, 1931
    - The Spiritual Possibilities of the Observance of the Lord's Day, 1931 (Box 139, Folder 2246)
    - Advantages of Testing Times, 1932-1935 (Box 139, Folder 2247)
    - How to Make the Past a Success, 1934
    - The Use of Time, 1934 (Box 139, Folder 2248)
    - Thoughts Out of My Life, 1935
    - Advantages of the Depression, 1936 (Box 139, Folder 2249)
    - Christ in Our Midst, 1936
    - Importance of Reaching the New Generation, 1936 (Box 139, Folder 2250)
    - The Youth of Tomorrow, 1939 (Box 139, Folder 2251)
    - Supreme Importance of Each Person's Having a Plan for His Life, 1940
    - El Cristiano, Embajador de Cristo, 1941 (Box 139, Folder 2252)
    - Rising Spiritual Tides, 1941
    - Habits of Fruitful Christian Living, 1943
    - Present Day Evangelism, 1944 (Box 139, Folder 2253)
    - Nine Pillars of Hope, 1947
    - Autobiographical, 1947 (Box 139, Folder 2254)
    - Lessons from Experience for Guidance in the New Year, 1947
    - What Will Heaven Be Like?, 1949 (Box 139, Folder 2255)
    - Christ Our Pattern in Religious Work, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 2256)
    - Christians of Reality, n.d.
    - The Field: Soul Saving in School and College (Box 139, Folder 2257)
    - The Importance of Spontaneity and Initiative in the Religious Life of Youth
    - The Importance of Christian Student Bands (Box 139, Folder 2257)
    - A Living Message and its Release
    - A Message to School Girls, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 2258)
    - The Need of a More Evangelistic Spirit, n.d.
    - Personal Work, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 2259)
    - The Place of Prayer in Our Work (with C.K. Ober), n.d.
    - The Secretary as an Evangelising Force, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 2260)
    - The Spiritual Life of the Secretary, n.d.
    - Winning the New Generation, n.d.
  - International Situation
    - General
      - The World Situation, 1913 (Box 139, Folder 2261)
      - Fostering Right Race Relations, 1914
      - An Unprecedented World Situation, 1914 (Box 139, Folder 2262)
      - World Topics, 1914
      - The International Country Life Outlook, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 2263)
      - Re: World Situation, 1917
      - The Church in the New World Situation, 1917 (Box 139, Folder 2264)
      - Re: World Situation, 1919
      - The Present International Situation (and the Responsibility of Men of Affairs), 1921, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 2265)
      - The Rebirth of the World, 1921 (Box 139, Folder 2266)
      - The Present Advantageous Position of the World-wide Christian Mevement, 1922
      - Second Day of God's Visitation, 1923 (Box 139, Folder 2267)
      - Statement sent to NY World re world situation, 1923
      - Students and the World Situation, 1925 (Box 139, Folder 2268)
      - The International Outlook and Unity in Service for World Peace, 1926 (Box 139, Folder 2269)
      - The Race Problem, 1926
      - World Trends and the Dedication of the Student's Life, 1928
      - Re: Tour of Far East, 1926 (Box 140, Folder 2269A)
      - Various JRM addresses in Australia Facing the Non-Christian World, 1926
      - Re: World Situation, 1927 (Box 140, Folder 2270)
      - Divisive and Unifying Influences in the Life of the World, 1929
      - Jesus Christ and Inter-racial Co-oporation for a Better World, 1929 (Box 140, Folder 2271)
      - The Present Unprecedented World Situation, 1930
      - The Present World Outlook, 1935 (Box 140, Folder 2272)
      - The Present World Situation, 1935
      - What Shall We Do? What Shall We Say?, 1937 (Box 140, Folder 2273)
      - The Present International Outlook, 1938
      - Light in Darkness, 1940, 1941 (Box 140, Folder 2274)
      - The Present World Situation and Suggestions on the Way Out, 1940, 1941
      - In Time of War, 1941 (Box 140, Folder 2275)
      - Lessons I Have Learned Over A Period of 60 Years in Organizing 5 World Christian Movements, 1946
      - Welt Ohne Zukunft?, 1946 (Box 140, Folder 2276)
      - The Present World Situation: Constructive First Steps, n.d. (Box 140, Folder 2277)
      - The Present World Situation and Some Ways in Which We May Answer that Need
      - An Unprecedented World Situation, n.d. (Box 140, Folder 2278)
    - Africa
      - The New Africa, 1935 (Box 140, Folder 2279)
    - Asia
      - Some Impressions of Missions in Asia, 1902 (Box 140, Folder 2280)
      - The Outlook in Asia, 1902
      - The Chinese Student Migration to Tokyo, 1908
      - The Urgency and Crisis in the Far East, 1908 (Box 140, Folder 2281)
      - Re: The United Theological College, Bangalore, 1912
      - Some Present-day Trends in the Life of the Orient, 1927 (Box 140, Folder 2282)
      - Grounds of Hope and Confidence that the Traditional Friendly and Co-operative Relations Between Japan and America Will Be Maintained, c. 1930
      - The Contribution of Christian Missions to the Orient, 1931 (Box 140, Folder 2283)
      - America Japan Society address, 1935
      - Forman Christian College address, 1936
      - Address at Consecration of Dornakal Cathedral, 1939 (Box 140, Folder 2284)
      - The Best is Before Us, c. 1946
      - Conferences of Students and Christian Workers in China (Box 140, Folder 2285)
      - Lessons for the Student Movement of the Occident from Experiences in Evangelistic Work Among the Students of the Orient, n.d.
    - Europe
      - Relations Between England and America During the Civil War, 1888 (Box 140, Folder 2286)
      - World Interest in the Evangelization of France, 1914
      - The Foreign Missionary Situation as Affected by the European War, c. 1917 (Box 140, Folder 2287)
      - European Conditions Today, c. 1924
      - Some Qutstanding Impressions of my Recent Trip to Eastern Europe and the Levant, 1924 (Box 140, Folder 2288)
    - Latin America
      - Advance Steps for the Evangelical Forces in Latin America..., 1941 (Box 140, Folder 2289)
      - The Claims of Latin America, 1940
    - Near East
      - Re: Near East Relief Work, 1924 (Box 140, Folder 2290)
      - America and the Golden Rule in the Near East (Box 140, Folder 2291)
    - Russia
      - Memorandum on Russia, 1911 (Box 140, Folder 2292)
      - Addresses given while on diplomatic mission in Russia, 1917 (Box 140, Folder 2293)
      - The Opportunity of the Hour in Russia and Other Countries, 1917 (Box 140, Folder 2294)
      - Address re diplomatic mission to Russia, 1917
      - A View of the Situation in Russia, 1918 (Box 140, Folder 2295)
      - Russia Holds the Fate of the Coming Years Re: Russia 1946, 1943 (Box 140, Folder 2296)
      - Re: Russia The Russian Theological Academy of n.d. St. Sergius - An Appraisal (Box 140, Folder 2297)
  - Missions
    - Wanted - Men for Foreign Missions, 1894 (Box 141, Folder 2298)
    - The Missionary Uprising Among the Young, c. 1895
    - Our Responsibility for the Extension of Christ's Kingdom into the Regions Beyond Re: Prayer and Missions 1900, 1898 (Box 141, Folder 2299)
    - The Find argement of the Native Arm of the Service Essential to the Highest Success of Missions Prayer and the Missionary Enterprise 1902 (Box 141, Folder 2300)
    - The Missionary Problem in its Relation to the College and University The Call of the Non-Christian World 1907, 1905 (Box 141, Folder 2301)
    - The Call to A Great Advance Call to an Unprecedented Advance in 1907 the Non-Christian World 2302A Modern World Movements: God's Chal- 1908 lenge to the Church The Crisis in Mission 1909 (Box 141, Folder 2302)
    - The College Students' Obligation to the Young Men of Rural Communities The Continuation Committee of World 1910 Missionary Conference, Edinburgh (Box 141, Folder 2303)
    - Re: Missionary Situation The Larger Co-operation of Laymen 1912 Imperative, 1910 (Box 141, Folder 2304)
    - Voices from the Field The Foreign Missionary Message 1913 Manners Uppgift i Varldmissionen 1913, 1912 (Box 141, Folder 2305)
    - Larger Usefulness Abroad The Present World Conflict and its 1915 Dec Relation to Christian Missions, 1917 (Box 141, Folder 2306)
    - Shall a World Program of Mission Be Launched while the World Is at War? The Hour of Christian Opportunity 1919, 1917 (Box 141, Folder 2307)
    - The Present Advantageous Position of Christian Missions Lessons Learned in Forty Years of Work 1925 in Helping to Establish and Develop National and International Student Christian Movements, 1920 (Box 141, Folder 2308)
    - New Forces Released Through Co-operation, 1925 (Box 141, Folder 2309)
    - Lessons Drawn from Rising Indigenous Churches Some Advantages of Co-operation 1926 (Box 141, Folder 2310)
    - Re: Missions What About Missions? c. 1930 Medical Missionary Enterprise - 1930 The Outlook Today, 1928, 1930 (Box 141, Folder 2311)
    - Strengthening the Home Base Meeting the World's Greatest Need 1932, 1931 (Box 141, Folder 2312)
    - A Message to the World Mission at a Time of Crisis (with Dutch translation) The Significance of the Appraisal 1932 Report of-the Laymen's Foreign Missions Inquiry, 1932, n.d. (Box 141, Folder 2313)
    - 30,000 Missionaries Facing Up to The World's Unfinished 1933 Problems, 1932 (Box 141, Folder 2314)
    - Be: Mission Our Greatest Triumphs Are Before Us c. 1935, 1934 (Box 141, Folder 2315)
    - At the Parting of the Ways The World Outlook and the World 1936 Mission The Rising Tide 1936, 1936-1937 (Box 141, Folder 2316)
    - The Challenge of the World Mission to Laymen The New Significance of Rural People 1937 to The Missionary Enterprise (Box 141, Folder 2317)
    - Christian as Ambassador (with French and German translations), 1939 (Box 141, Folder 2318)